

Jr. Full Stack Web Developer | www.abelista.com | 310.967.9311

auxhernandez@mac.com • https://github.com/shotbyabel

ABOUT ME

I first developed a passion for programming during a coding workshop. The realization that I could contribute the knowledge and experience I gained from twelve years in the Entertainment industry to the tech world and create new services and products that would positively impact people's lives motivated me to dive into web development full-time. Having spent 600+ hours in 3 months learning and building web applications at General Assembly's immersive bootcamp and since November 2015 working for a new ambitious start-up I am confident that my combination of creative and technical skills will contribute positively to your team.

WEB DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

Front End: , HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS, jQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap, Ionic Mobile framework, Materialize, Semantic UI Back End: Node JS, MongoDB, Expressjs, Firebase, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, foundations of PHP & mySQL

OTHER SKILLS

Photography & Video: Adobe Premiere & Photoshop, Canon 5D full frame Camera, Canon Lens and flash/lights remote accessories. Audio Engineering: Pro Tools HD, Vintage and Modern Microphone techniques, Multi-track consoles & digital effects processors. Language & Culture: Proficient in Spanish and conversational Portuguese. Self-reliant and independent with cultural competence.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

LabTech (a4c.us), AngularJs & Mobile Developer.

November 2015 • Hollywood, CA

Interacting with our teams in Beijing & Paris along with my colleagues we are implementing a dynamic framework like AngularJS to an international business model on the mobile side with Ionic framework and scaling an existing API with PHP functions on the Back End & mysql Database.

Brainitch, AngularJs Front End Developer

October 2015 • Los Angeles, CA

Using Angular Js dynamic directives my task was to build pages with a couple different forms for user registration and login for a Single Page Application using ui-router. These included custom validation parameters for better UX & send data to the back-end via \$http. All responsive and build with pure CSS3.

Water Hackathon @ Rhubarb Studios

August 2015 ● Los Angeles, CA

I assisted our team on developing the Front End look of our 'Water Wars' app. I used the Materialize CSS framework and created the forms to register and login users with EJS and in conjunction I built the routes on the node.js and Express back-end for these particular views.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Capital Audio & Royal Z Entertainment

Office & Client account Coordinator

Feb 2011- June 2015 ● Burbank, CA

Originally appointed to be in charge of the collections department. With my efforts the company began to recuperate \$50,000 within fifteen months from past due accounts. With this performance, prior technical knowledge & my client relation experience I was promoted to handle our client's accounts & our office administration. My duties consisted of daily interaction with domestic & international record labels representatives, producers, artist & studio managers. We were trusted with coordinating & facilitating music production/performances of artists like: Kanye West, Dr. Luke and Pharrell Williams, to name a few.

Warner Bros.

Lead Audience Coordinator

Dec 2009 - Apr 2011 ● Burbank, CA

I started as a **clerk floater** for the Tour Department and assisted managers & tour guides with administrative tasks & soundstage security **for the** Warner Bros Studio lot. Soon after I began to assist on the *Ellen Degeneres* show with guest services on the ingress/egress of over 300 people. After a two month tour, the department management appointed me **lead audience coordnator** to supervise a team of seven guest services employees to ensure studio safety guidelines are observed while we made sure all of Telepictures's production requests **were** met for the tapings of *Lopez Tonight & Conan O'brien* TV shows.

Viva Vision!

Post Production Assistant & Spanish Linguist

Aug 2008 - Sept 2009 ● Santa Monica, CA

I was introduced to photography & began my work as a translator/linguist. My initial duties were to translate mobile app content into Spanish. Brand Managers & Photographers began to entrust me with new responsibilities in which I thrived. This led to PA roles during location & set shoots. Soon after I was responsible for the content management of four mobile apps which included the post production of photographs using Adobe Photoshop, and uploading and entering metadata into contact management system. I was able to improve overall products & maximized revenue by creating new categories & acquiring new content.

Paramount Recording Group

Assistant Studio Manager

Aug 2004 - Aug 2008 • Los Angeles, CA

From the beginning as a studio runner I was liked & trusted by music producers & artist. I ensured all janitorial, administrative & client services task were completed efficiently for all our clients & management. I learned to anticipate clients' needs & started to reorganize staffs' priorities & responsibilities, which led to an assistant management position. I was responsible for coordinating many successful recording & mixing sessions under minimal supervision. Here I learned & thrive the most at being a liaison between executives, producers, artists & audio engineers.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY • Web Development Immersive Program & Front End Development• April 2015 - September 2015 • Los Angeles, CA FULL SAIL UNIVERSITY • Associate of Science in Audio Engineering • 2000-2002 • Orlando, FL